I heard that now in
Я слышал что сейчас получается э в
Russia there is a huge shortage of these uh
России огромнейшая нехватка этих ээ
district inspectors investigators there in
участковых инспекторов следователей там
general there is a huge shortage going on there is a huge
вообще огромная нехватка идёт огромная
shortage they recently called me from the
нехватка мне недавно звонили они с
HR department I didn’t even pick up the phone
отдела кадров Я даже трубку не взял
go I said Because they need people
идите я сказал Потому что им нужны люди
now I’m there in general I’m completely
сейчас я там вообще полный
lass Oh my gosh  United State of amica
лас Опа себе United State of amica
Yes, why is that so? I come from Rostov myself.
Да а почему так Я сам родом из Ростова
But I’ve been living in California for 18 years. In 2
Но 18 лет живу в Калифорнии уже через 2
years I’ll be
года будет
[music]
[музыка]
twenty tags - this is Samara or Which
двадцать талья - это Самарская или Какая
region of
область
Samara my dad once served in the
самарска меня батя когда-то служил в
Samara region and
Самарской области а
I don’t remember where  he was small. He once
где не помню я был мелкий Мне как-то он
told me that in the Samara region,
рассказывал что в Самарской области
what year and the water of the first a ba is the same age as
какого года и воде первого а ба ровесник
you know, yes, when ba is already Bath for
понимаете да он когда ба уже Бат уже 70
more than 70 years, Bat is no longer yes Bat is no longer
лет с лишним Бат уже нет да Бат уже нет
dead, well, it’s just, well, it’s already time and
умер ну просто ну время уже да
old, it just turns out that
старенький просто получается что он
when he told the Samara region to me,
когда рассказывал самарскую область мне
little one, I will clarify which
же малому я что там буду уточнять какой
Gorodok is there. I now understand that different
Городка Это я сейчас понимаю что разные
people most likely served in Riga and was
го скорее всего служил на рижу и был
a motorized rifleman, I don’t know, but I
мотострелок не знаю ну а я
served, it turned out to be such a problem, all my
служил получилась такая вот беда все мои
friends who served in the Samara region
друзья Кто служил в Самарской области
all served  Samara region and I was
все служили Самарской области а меня
thrown into the Sverdlovsk region Yes Vla
свердловскую область закинул Да Вла
Far away and there
Далеко и там
Ponya Well, I haven’t been for 18 years, my
Поня Ну я уже 18 лет не был у меня
parents live in Rostov Yes, but I haven’t
родители в Ростове живут Да но я не
come for 18 years, that is, they came to me,
приезжал уже 18 лет то есть они ко мне
I didn’t come, you live in America
приезжали я не приезжал вы в Америке
right now and in  California Sacramento
прямо живёте да в Калифорнии Сакраменто
And you're straight And which ones are straight drowning which ones I'm
А вы пря А какие прям топите какие я
not at all this I'm a scientist I'm not And these
вообще не этот я учёный я не А эти
football there are not generally a sport against chess
футбол там не вообще спорт проти шахматы
chess about chess - it's not a sport it's like that,
шахматы о шахматы - это не спорт это так
it's a serious idea Yes, the mine is a
это затея серьёзно Да шахта это затея
money-making, expensive idea, I understand, like Golf
денежная дорогая затея понял как и Golf
yes And what are you talking about here, I’m just sitting here
да А Вы о чём тут общаетесь просто сижу
drinking a beer, I’m sitting just talking without any
выпил пиво сижу просто общаюсь без какой
politics If you want politics Well, yes,
политики Если хотите политику Ну мне да
I’m interested. For example, I don’t want to.
мне интересно Вот напри Я не хочу Да
Look, the fact is that I, uh, work
смотрите де в том что я ээ работаю на
part-time in a news publication here in
полставки в новостном издании у нас в
Sacramento and because  I kind of know the
Сакраменто и поскольку я как бы знаю
Russian language, I undertook to write in
русский язык я взялся писать в
this American publication about Russia
американском это издании о России потому
because the Americans, when even Tucker
что американцы когда вот даже Такер
Carlson came, but he doesn’t understand
Карлсон он приезжал но он не понимает
us, you know, he came there, they
нас понимаете он приехал его там что-то
took him around the metro for something, he listened to Putin,
поводили по метро всё он послушал Путина
but he doesn’t understand ours  mentality
но он не понимает наш менталитет ему
is difficult for him to convey to understand the main messages I
сложно донести понять главные месседжи Я
understand Because I grew up Even under the
понимаю Потому что я вырос ещё Даже при
Union Yes, since the eighty-first year you, I will
Союзе Да с восемьдесят первого года вы я
interrupt you, there are Russian jokes that an
вас перебью есть шутки русские которые
American cannot understand. Well, for example,
понять американец не может А ну например
let’s say a ship there and or, well, such
корабле допустим там и либо ну такие
jokes as go fishing and  take you
шутки типа пойти на рыбалку и взять с
fishing with you, that’s
собой на рыбалку это это же к
bad luck,
беде
let’s say I’m like that. I’ve already
допустим Всё я так по Я уже американцем
become an American along the way. You’ve been an American for a long time that you won’t
по ходу стал Вы давно Американ что не
catch just you. Well, like,
поймаете только только вас
she’ll teach you, you can’t do that, that’s
Ну типа она будет вас учить так нельзя
how it’s like, taking you fishing is
это так это так взять на рыбалку это
generally a
вообще
disaster. It’s old.  In general, this is a Russian joke,
беда Это старая вообще это русская шутка
hay or something. I’ve just
сено что ли Я просто рыбалкой не
never been into fishing, it’s obvious, well,
увлекался никогда то видно ну Серьёзно
this is serious. One of these is a simple
это вот Одна из таких это простет кая
joke. What other jokes are we even
шутка ту Какие ещё шутки вот даже
allowed? Now I’ve started rewatching
допустим сейчас я начал пересматривать
the series Friends, friends, I’m sitting watching and they have
сериал Друзья друзья сижу смотрю и у них
such jokes about
такие приколы
the explosion of the series  there is one
взрыва е сериал есть такой
you know Oh, I advise you to watch this
знаете Ой я вам советую посмотреть это
great series The Big Bang Theory
шикарный сериал Теория большого взрыва
it’s just a great series
это просто это шикарный сериал Два раза
I watched it twice and there are jokes and I understand
посмотрел его и там шутки и я понимаю
that they are translated into Russian Well, our
что переведены на русский язык Ну наш
joke Well, it’s clear that these jokes are ours Well,
прикол Ну понятно эти приколы наши их Ну
I understand that our jokes are
я понятно что наши приколы
different  I can’t even remember everything even
разные я не могу даже вспомнить се даже
on the ship you didn’t understand
на корабле уже вы не поняли
I didn’t understand what the
не я не понял в чём
joke was on the ship if you took it on the ship
шутка на корабле если взяли на корабль
firstly you won’t catch anything and
вы во-первых ничего не поймаете а
secondly she will lead you What
во-вторых она будет вами руководить Что
will you
вы будете
do Like at home Like at home she
делать Как дома Как дома она
be it in California Yes, we
буде кака Калифорнии Да мы раз в месяц
go on a yacht once a month and we take women also
на яхте катаемся и женщин берём тоже
normally, and
нормально и А
why did they
зачем при
catch us in Russia? Well, if you
ловили вме у нас в России Ну если
took a woman on the ship, either she is your
женщина взяла на корабль либо она твоя
wife or you rented her. Well,
жена либо ты её взяла на прокат Ну а в
what’s the problem with the wife or  ride on a ship with a girl
чём проблема с женой или с девушкой на
Okay, we won’t Well, it’s
корабле покататься Ладно не будем Ну это
generally different Yes Funny Why did he
вообще разный Да Прикол Почему так
become so far from us And damn, you just see, my
далеко стал от нас А блин просто видишь
brain is somehow not adapted to Jokes for this, I
я уже мозгами как-то к Шуткам этим не
even understood How much is your
приспособлен даже понял А сколько у вас
salary there now in
сейчас там зарплата в
Russia average here I am now  I am a pensioner, I am a
России средне вот я сейчас я пенсионер я
military pensioner, my pension is very small,
военный у меня пенсия очень маленькая
20,000, my pension is 20,200
20.000 у меня пенсия 20 200
dollars, I don’t know the dollar, well, it’s worth 100,200
долларов я не знаю долла ну на 100 200
dollars. Yes, it turns out to be 200 dollars.  it
долларов Да 200 долларов получается мо
was
лет отработал на государство а было
less it was less even before that they gave me
меньше было меньше ещё до этого это мне
another
ещё
raise Wait, this is also some kind of
повысили Подожди это это тоже какая-то
Russian joke that I can’t understand,
русская шутка которую я не могу понять
just yes
просто да
I get a 20,000 ruble pension, we do
Я получаю 20.000 руб пенсию у нас это
n’t call it a pension, but payments for
называется не пенсия а выплаты по
long service, I worked all my life for the
лет я всю жизнь отработал на
state I  I paid off two mortgages personally,
государство Я две ипотеки отплатил лично
I paid off two mortgages while working for the state, I
две ипотеки работая на государство я
paid off two
выплатил две
mortgages with my own money, yes,
ипотеки своими деньгами понял да меня
my state understood me, but
моему государству Сим но
that’s how I hate my state. I
вот так вот Я ненавижу сво государство Я
never voted for Putin.
за Путина не голосовал никогда
And who voted for him,
никогда А кто же за него голосовал
probably? My neighbors, I understand
наверно Мои соседи Я так понял
how  You haven’t been in
авал как давно вы не
the military for a long time 2 years 2 years And in which
военный 2 года 2 с по года А в каких
troops
войсках
were there ex-mi
были эксми
then in these
тогда в этих
troops if someone like you
войсках если кого-то типа ли вы
established the reason with and I Yes, well, I am,
устанавливали причину с и у меня Да ну я
yes, otherwise you understand the Ministry of Internal Affairs of the Ministry of Internal Affairs and and I have a
да а то вы поняли МВД МВД и и у меня
military pension now  Yes, it's you, the Ministry of Internal Affairs,
военной пенсии сейчас Да это Это вы МВД
Yes, yes, I had a military pension, it's
Да да да Я был у меня военная пенсия
considered that you're not military, you're, well, well, well, well,
считается это вы не военные вы А ну ну
we're straight down to one to one. I
на Ну у нас один к одному прямо сводят
understood, I
Всех понял
understood, and I understood everything for 20 years. I studied in Wuxi and
понял и я всю всю все 20 лет Я учился
needed advanced training.
уся повышение квалификации мне надо было
confirm my qualifications And the salary
подтверждать мою квалификацию А зарплату
I received was the same as
Я получал одинаковый как
the teaching staff, this
ППС меня вот это
infuriated me. I give you a promotion and he just walks the
бесило Я повышаю а он просто ходит по
streets. Day after day I heard that
улицам Да по день за днм идт слышал что
in Russia now there is a huge
сейчас получается в России огромнейшая
shortage of these district inspectors.
нехватка этих участковых инспекторов
They called the HR department. I
звонили они отдела кадров Я даже трубку
didn’t even
не
pick up the phone, I said.  Because they need people
взял я сказал Потому что им нужны люди
now, I’m generally in total
сейчас я там вообще полный полная
chaos there, we have a new law published in
разруха у нас новый закон издали в
Russia now we can’t allow VKontakte to be
России сейчас нельзя допустим ВКонтакте
discussed somewhere Well, the government Well, I didn’t
обсуждать Ну правительства Ну не я
look What they didn’t publish in armor, it was also
смотрел Что не издали лат егоже
published from afar years in prison 80,000 fine or these
издали года тюрьмы 80.000 штраф либо эти
detentions
отработки
Cool, I’m all  I deleted my posts
Прикольно я я все свои посты удалил пря
right away But because I don’t want
моментально Но потому что не хочется
to sit Well,
сидеть Ну
yes, you worked You know what kind of system it is
да работали Вы знаете что это за система
Yes, it’s completely honest here in
Да это полный честно у нас вот у нас в
Taglyati, I’ll tell you more here when the chief
Тальяти я скажу вам больше у нас когда
leaves, let’s say a colonel
уходит нача допустим полковник уходит
retires on vacation goes on vacation  he is
на пенсию в отпуск уходит в отпуск его
replaced by a deputy deputy and there is no one to
замещает заместитель зам а некого
appoint Captain police captain
ставить Капитан капитан полиции
T Captain this only happened during the war,
Т Капитан такое было только в войну
probably yes, the Great Patriotic War when there
наверное да Великую Отечественную когда
was a shortage I don’t know Captain captain
нехватка была не знаю Капитан капитан
head of the police department Well, this is funny
начальник отдела полиции Ну это смешно
funny at least There are no majors left, that’s
смешно минимум Майоров не осталось вот в
the problem and where did they all
чём вот проблема а куда они делись все
go?  I have a
уходят у меня вот жена
new wife, not an old one, from
новая не ста ровени при с
where she doesn’t know anything, she
откуда ничего не знает это раньше
used to work as a justice investigator before the police,
милиции работала следователем юстиции
the investigator retired, she came to
следователь ушла на пенсию пришла
turn the nuts, the man ran away from there
крутить гайки убежал человек оттуда
to turn the nuts, they
чтобы гайки крутить
caught the criminal and I’m
поймали преступника и меня у
not honest, what should I do?
амло ни честно что мне делать надо ещ
Hello, what?
Здравствуйте Что у вас
it happened to you Well, just like that, it’s half a
случилось Ну вот так вот так это пол
job
работа
[music] the
[музыка]
system was finalized right up until retirement, they
система доработали аж до пенсии раньше
didn’t leave earlier Because to receive a pension,
не ушли Потому что бы пенсию получать
I only had to work for six months before
мне оставалось работать полгода до
retirement I say, I’m quitting I came
пенсии Я говорю я увольняюсь Я пришёл
home, I’m saying I’m quitting, he wears me down, he
домой говорю я увольняюсь он меня носит
says you, you endured  they are 20 years old and in
говорит ты ты терпел их 20 лет и за
six months you will leave. I say, I’m sitting there thinking.
полгода ты уйдёшь Я говорю сижу думаю А
Yes, seriously. Why would I
да серьёзно А что бы я пенсию же буду
receive my pension correctly? I stayed. Well, how I
получать правильно я остался я Ну как я
worked out, I was on sick leave, I was on sick leave.
доработал я я на больни ках сидел я на
Well, I understand, I was sick there, how
больничных Ну понял да там болел как
long did it last and left?  that's all for retirement and you
тыпы дотянул и ушёл на пенсию всё и
're still working somewhere else now. Well, of course I'm
работаете где-то сейчас ещё Ну конечно я
now Oh oh, everything's fine with me now.
сейчас Ой ой у меня сейчас всё прекрасно
I have my own flower
У меня сейчас свой цветочный
shop. I'm doing fine. Now I'm
магазин У меня всё хорошо Сейчас на себя
not officially working for myself. I won't
работаю не официально не буду ничего
say anything, otherwise the tax authorities will catch me now.
говорить а то сейчас меня это накроет
You  this is a Streamer blogger Yes
налоговое Вы же это Стример блогер Да
Streamer blogger Well, I understand, yes Not
Стример блогер Ну я понял да Не у меня
everything is fine with me, now I’m having a blast I’m doing
всё прекрасно сейчас я кайфую У меня
great now I’m just based on this from the
сейчас всё отлично Я просто по этим по
police, yes, I read in the Belgorod
полиции да я читал в Белгородской
region they wrote that there is
области писали что там в этих
generally enough in these border areas
приграничных территориях вообще хватает
Because firstly, salaries  such that
Потому что во-первых зарплата такая что
people really go to other jobs
люди действительно на другие работы идут
with less risk with less. You as a security guard
с меньшим риском с меньшим ты охранником
in Pyaterochka get more than a
в Пятёрочке получаешь больше чем
policeman like the one who runs around and shoots
полицейский типа который бегает стреляет
bandits. Well, you say, no, I don’t pretend
бандитов Ну ну вы говорите Да не не кажу
that I read the taco. I don’t know how much
что я читал тако Я не знаю насколько
it is, well, I agree,
оно ну я соглашусь
I’m still working.  even an expert
я я работаю ещ даже экспертом
criminologist, an expert criminologist, I’ll
криминалистом эксперт-криминалист я вам
explain it to you like medicine, it’s like an oncologist,
объясню это как медицине это как онколог
let’s say a surgeon. Well, of course, a
допустим хирург Ну понятно специалист
narrow specialist. I confirmed my qualifications,
узкий Я подтверждал свою квалификацию
studied but received the same salary
учился но получал зарплату такую же как
as a local pediatrician. I think that this is
и участковый педиатр Я считаю что это
wrong, in Russia, this is how it is,
неправильно вот в России вот так
this is true.  I won’t even lie.
вот это правда Это правда даже врать не
I think that in Russia the Ministry of Internal Affairs system is
буду Я считаю что в России система МВД
completely destroyed, it’s just that everything is
полностью разрушена вот просто на все
straight
прям
100, first of all, it doesn’t put anything at all, everyone
100 во-первых не ставит вообще никак все
sends the salary is minimal in general.
посылают зарплата минимальна вообще
Peaceful, the demands are great, well who
Мирная ещё требования велики хорошо кто
goes to this whole Amon who
же идт в этот весь Амон который
disperses the protesters with batons,
дубинками разгоняет
this is the National Guard  another thing
митингующих это уже росгвардия другое
I know is that
зна это
they used to
аво раньше
be that I don’t know unknown
были что я не знаю неведом
security, I understand in Russia they were like that
охрана понял в России такая была вот
too, they are the same department I don’t know what
тоже туда же они яже отде Я не знаю что
they are paid there like I don’t
им там платят как и этих я не
touch these people I understand I’m just talking And your
касаюсь понял я говор просто А ваши
employees are there too so before
которые сотрудники что там тоже так до
Everyone lives out their pensions,
пенсии доживают все
thank God, the worst thing was the deputy
у слава Богу всё самое страшное был зам
head of the Internal Affairs Directorate, we had a good person, the
начальника УВД у нас был хороший человек
rate is awesome, the last name is
проценка офигенная фамилия у
Protsenko, Ukrainian. Well, I guess I don’t know,
Проценко украинец Ну наверное я не знаю
he died. He died, and honestly, when did
вот он умер Вот он умер и честно когда
he die? I saw VKontakte. I’m sorry.
он умер Я видел ВКонтакте Мне жалко
Ivanovich was a very good man.  we all the
очень хороший человек был Иваныч мы всё
time called him Ivanych Ivanych Ivanych
время называли его Иваныч Иваныч Иваныч
And so he died to me It’s a pity that he
И вот он умер мне Вот его жалко от
died of old age or I don’t think we’ll just
старости умер или я не я думаю просто
prank his heart How old he is, he’s the
сердечко пошалим его Какая старость он
same as me, maybe a little older than me
такой же как я может чуть постарше меня
and I always say they should
и я всегда говорю надо
have written on time Yes yes yes yes  you do
вовремя написали Да да да надо вовремя
n’t have to endure it in time, that’s
не надо терпеть вот это
all Good luck, good health to you, good
вот всё Удачи здоровь тебе хорошо давай
job in general Uh-
вообще молодец
huh Russian jokes like pips comment
Угу русские шутки лайк пипс комент
subscribe to my Telegram right now
подпишись на мий Telegram прямо зараз
autumn and so much
осень а
more and more respectfully YouTube Zaga
пок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube Зага
us through srg or in your ban and I
нас через срг ор в твый бан и дуже
don’t show much more video  People are constantly not
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
showing information about the stream. To that end, in order for
показуе информация про стрими Тому для
Mali to write an operational link
того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок
right away, in the meantime, in Telegra
пишиться прямо зараз а пок там в телегра
okm Vdeo ezh Tsikava and Korisna
окм вдео ще теж цикава и корисна
information and we pon vama
информация и мы пон вама
postiyny operational link is
постийний оперативный звязок
independent in that chi show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава Украине
pipis L
пидпись L